Rubing Guo

Database Analyst at UAMS - University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences

rubingkuo@gmail.com

Summary

Experience in software development, design, and algorithm related environment:

- Software engineering internship
- Teaching assistant in CS courses

Skills: C++/C, Java, J2EE, Object Oriented Programming, SQL, Database, Shell Scripting, HTML, CSS, PHP, Ruby, Bootstrap, JavaScript, SAS Programming, MS Access, Linux Command Line.

Email me if you're interested: rubingkuo@gmail.com

Experience

Database Analyst at UAMS - University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences

January 2017 - Present (2 months)

Software Developer at BBA Solutions

May 2016 - November 2016 (7 months)

Mostly use Ruby on Rails, MVC, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, DB, SQL, GIT and so on. Websites I have built are listed below,

huffmanandcompany.com

don-pepes.com

rubingguo.com

tonysmithlaw.com

Research Assistant, Intelligent Autonomous Systems Laboratory, UALR. at University of Arkansas

September 2014 - May 2016 (1 year 9 months)

Applied the SIFT and SURF descriptor to SLAM and studied the difference between their performances. Developed a method to detect and recognize human activities using a single IMU.

Professional Intern at Nanjing Baoyan Automation Co. Ltd

September 2012 - June 2013 (10 months)

- Designed models and examined errors using Auto-CAD;
- Converted the STL files into a series of thin layers for 3D printing;

Certifications

C Language Certification

Computer and Test Center of Jiangsu Province University License 0232402113 December 2011

Java Tutorial

SoloLearn License 10683241669 February 2017

Education

University of Arkansas at Little Rock

Master of Science (MS), Computer Science, 2014 - 2016

Nanjing Normal University

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.), Electrical and Electronics Engineering, 2010 - 2014

Skills & Expertise

Algorithms

Java

C++

 \mathbf{C}

JavaScript

Ruby on Rails

HTML5

CSS

Bootstrap

Data Analysis

SAS Programming

Databases

Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)

Matlab

Shell Scripting

Linux

Microsoft Access

SQL

Projects

Human Activity Detection and Classification using IMU Data

January 2016 to March 2016

Members: Rubing Guo

Get the raw data from IMU, including acceleration and angular rate from accelerometer and Gyroscope separately.

Using the thigh angle computed from the information fusion of acc and gyro, to classify the human activity, with the preparation of mounting the IMU on the thigh, Gx represents the movement forward and backward.

The whole process comes with

Get raw data using C++, then apply butterfly filter to remove noise from the raw data, get thigh angle calculation, zero detection, human activity classification, including walking, running, standing, sitting.

A Comparative Study of SIFT and SURF's Performances in SLAM

January 2016 to May 2016

Members: Rubing Guo, Soonhac Hong

Apply SIFT and SURF descriptor separately to detect the feature on the sequence 3D images derived from 3D camera, the outliers of the feature matching process is removed by RANSAC.

Followed by calculating the Pose Changes between matched points using SVD.

The PCs are then optimized by Pose Graph Optimization.

SIFT and SURF's performance in the VRO-PGO process are compared through accuracy comparison and efficiency comparison.

The conclusion is SURF is much slower than SIFT using SLAM(VRO-PGO), the main reason is the RANSAC process takes much longer time than SIFT, and the accuracy consistency is worse than that of SIFT, from the result we got, the mean error of the method based on SURF performs four times greater than SIFT based method, and the computational time of SURF-SLAM is thousands more than SIFT-SLAM.

Volunteer Experience

Editor at Nanjing Daily Media Group

July 2012 - Present

Courses

Master of Science (MS), Computer Science

University of Arkansas at Little Rock

Spatial Time Series SYEN 5352

Linux Systems Programming SYEN 5308

Math Statistics I MATH 7350

Math Statistics II MATH 7351

Real-Time Embedded Sytems SYEN 7306

Parallel Processing CPSC 7312

Image Processing CPSC 7374

Languages

English(Native or bilingual proficiency)Manderin(Native or bilingual proficiency)French(Limited working proficiency)

Rubing Guo

Database Analyst at UAMS - University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences

rubingkuo@gmail.com



1 person has recommended Rubing

"I shared a research group with Rubing at University of Arkansas for a year starting Fall of 2015. I found her to be hardworking, diligent and smart. She happened to be a quick learner and was never afraid to ask questions. She showed herself to be a good problem solver. She maintained a healthy working relationship with all the colleagues in the group. Overall she is a well rounded individual who is keen to grow and learn."

— **Muhammad Emaduddin**, *Research Associate*, *University of Arkansas at Little Rock*, worked directly with Rubing at University of Arkansas

Contact Rubing on LinkedIn